Cool. So classes can have class methods on them. Those are methods that are shared among
all the instances of a certain type. They can be overwritten in a specific instance or sub-class.
And in order to do that, you have to add what's called an annotation over that method.
Called class method to say that this method does not expect an instance on it.
Instead, you get a variable called class or CLS, whatever you want to call it.
You should not name it CLSS because that is a keyword. So you might see something like this.
If you see this, you might also see it called CLAZZ just so that it doesn't override this keyword here.
And this lets you access some of the variables that are defined in the class. So now I can
access class.runs and class.number of wheels. So I know that all of my car classes are going to have
four wheels. And so this method can be shared between all of the instances.
We can, though, just override that in our instance itself. If I make a new my car instance,
I can set number of wheels to six. That will only affect that one instance.
Now, just like we used type on the Ripple, there are two more helper methods that you can use.
Is instance and is subclass to tell you what if a particular variable is an instance of a particular class.
So for example, let's try these out. I can ask Python, if I know the type of 42,
and I know the type of a string, I can ask Python is instance 42 int and I should get true.
Can I also ask is instance the string high int? No. Is instance high stir this will return true?
And I can do the same thing for the objects that I define.
So here, let's exit out of the Ripple. I can print out is instance my other car,
car, and run this, and we'll see that it is true. So if you need to investigate what's going on
with your objects or your instances, is instance and is subclass will help you figure out those answers.
One other method I want to talk to you about in classes is this optional magic method called
we haven't talked about magic methods just yet. Magic methods are defined by having two underscores
before and after them. That means that there's something special about these functions, these methods.
So in this case, Dunder in it, Dunder stands for double underscores, is going to get run when you
create an instance of that class. And you can do that Dunder in it method. You can use that method
to define any scenarios or set up that you need when an instance is being created,
including setting instance variables so that you can save what is passed into that constructor
to use for later. So let's copy this and take a look at it.
This is the my car class just like we had, but I've added a Dunder in it method here.
Remember it's an it's axon and instance. So I need to pass in self first. I can also pass in
make and a model. These are required arguments. So if I don't pass these in,
instantiation will fail. Now if I want to save those values to use later, I need to save them
on the instance just like this. Once I save them on the instance, that means that I can use them
later on when I call other methods on them. So here when I call my car equals car forward and
Thunderboard and I call start. I will print out that my forward Thunderbird is started
room room. There are other magic methods that you might come across. One is
Thunderster, the other is Thunderrepper and these are two handy magic methods that are useful for
debugging. You can think of and they both return a string. You can think of Thunderster as the
representation of your object that should be human readable. Something that you can pass back to
the end user to let them know how this object is represented. Whereas Thunderrepper should return
the Python code that's maybe necessary to rebuild the object. So Thunderrepper is used more for
under the hood, a representation for other programmers, a representation for debugging. And that's
kind of the difference. If you take a look at what is returned from date time dot date time dot now,
which just creates a new object with the current date and time. If you take a look at the
store representation, you'll see that there's a date and a timestamp. If you take a look at the
wrapper, it will let you know that this is a date time dot date time. And these are the arguments
that you would pass into that method in order to recreate it. These are just conventions. You
don't have to follow them, but you will see these throughout Python code. Generally, you do want
to have a stir and a wrapper in each of your classes. Know that you can also instantiate objects
in four loops or in less comprehension. So a lot of these concepts are mixed and matched.